<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linux on Pawka&#39;s diary</title>
    <link>https://pawka.notrollsallowed.com/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux on Pawka&#39;s diary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pawka.notrollsallowed.com/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>TIL: Configure Pulseaudio to not switch output to hot-plugged devices</title>
      <link>https://pawka.notrollsallowed.com/posts/2021-05-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawka.notrollsallowed.com/posts/2021-05-07/</guid>
      <description>:til: :linux:
Motivation I have Blue Yeti USB microphone which also has an audio output for monitoring. I do not use the output but once pluged-in - Ubuntu recognize it as new sound card and switch output to the microphone immediatelly. This drives me nuts because I always need to switch back audio output manually to previous device.
Pulseaudio config Pulseaudio has a feature automatically switch to hot-plugged devices which is enabled by default.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux RAM kompresija su zram</title>
      <link>https://pawka.notrollsallowed.com/posts/2020-11-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawka.notrollsallowed.com/posts/2020-11-10/</guid>
      <description>:linux:
Darbinis kompiuteris vargsta dėl atminties trūkumo. Mat turi tik 16G RAM&amp;rsquo;o. Dirbame su monorepo ir tam tikri monolitinės repozitorijos įrankiai kaip gazelle arba gopls reikalauja nemažai atminties ir kartais skubiai. Jei dar fone paleistas koks Spotify, Goole Chrome, Slack&amp;rsquo;as - visas RAM&amp;rsquo;o valgytojų elitas - tai kažkas turi pasitraukti.
Būna, paleidus gazelle kompas pakimba ir atsigauna po kažkiek laiko. Būna atsigauna su baltu Slack&amp;rsquo;o langu (nes tam pritrūko atminties kažką sukramtyt).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TIL: Spotify media keys on Linux</title>
      <link>https://pawka.notrollsallowed.com/posts/2020-09-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawka.notrollsallowed.com/posts/2020-09-07/</guid>
      <description>:til: :linux:
It seems Chrome is capturing media keys handling and Spotify can not be controlled with the keys. This can be solved by visiting chrome://flags/#hardware-media-key-handling and disabling &amp;ldquo;Hardware Media Key Handling&amp;rdquo; option.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XKB and keyboard layouts on Linux</title>
      <link>https://pawka.notrollsallowed.com/posts/2020-08-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawka.notrollsallowed.com/posts/2020-08-31/</guid>
      <description>:linux:
For a while I was looking for an efficient way to deal with Lithuanian letters and english keyboard at the same time. I have noticed that switching between keyboard layouts with Super+Space (or any other keys combination) is not efficient. Sometimes I even do not recognize when I switch to different layout and start typing code. Or jump from chat to vim and instead of special symbols lithuanian letters are written.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
