<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>coding on Pawka&#39;s diary</title>
    <link>https://pawka.notrollsallowed.com/tags/coding/</link>
    <description>Recent content in coding on Pawka&#39;s diary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pawka.notrollsallowed.com/tags/coding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Solving Advent of Code 2019</title>
      <link>https://pawka.notrollsallowed.com/posts/2020-12-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawka.notrollsallowed.com/posts/2020-12-31/</guid>
      <description>:coding:
After solving AoC 2020, it became so empty inside so I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to look into tasks from 2019. But the real truth is that I&amp;rsquo;ve heard AoC 2019 consist series of CPU-emulator problems named Intcode. This sounds very interesting for me and I wanted to check.
I&amp;rsquo;ll keep updating this while solving the problems.
Problems Day 1 (easy): Arithmetic. Day 2 (easy): Basic emulator (Intcode). I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to build and reuse the same CPU class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mokau dukrą programuoti Scratch</title>
      <link>https://pawka.notrollsallowed.com/posts/2020-12-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawka.notrollsallowed.com/posts/2020-12-29/</guid>
      <description>:coding:
Mano vyresnijąjai dukrai Ievai - 7 metai. Pirmokė. Kadangi COVID-o dėka vaikų atostogos pailgėjo viena savaite ir vietoj 2 tapo 3, galvojau kokia naudinga veikla reiktų užimti vaiką. Prisiminiau, kad egzistuoja programavimo aplinka Scratch. Pats Scratch&amp;rsquo;o niekada nebuvau bandęs ar naudojęs, tad tik teoriškai įsivaizdavau kas tai yra. Tiesa, dabar miglotai prisiminiau, kad pažįstamas Jurgis Pralgauskis prieš kokius 10 metų demonstravo per vieną iš Ubuntu release-party susitikimų.
Scratch&amp;rsquo;as ant Windows&amp;rsquo;ų atrodo geriau, nei and Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2020</title>
      <link>https://pawka.notrollsallowed.com/posts/2020-12-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawka.notrollsallowed.com/posts/2020-12-27/</guid>
      <description>:coding:
This year was the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve decided or even tried to participate in Advent of Code (AoC) challenge. Since it was the first attempt I had no clue what to expect. I haven&amp;rsquo;t participated in competitive challenges ever though I&amp;rsquo;ve solved some similar tasks on Hackerank or other pages. I haven&amp;rsquo;t competed for time because the every day task is opened at 7AM. Exactly the time when I prepare breakfast for my kids, bring them to school/kindergarten and after return - need to start work on my job (not on AoC).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
